One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
One Pace Premium Keep the project alive: ko-fi.com/not6ip
After their guide Pekoms disappeared, Luffy's team left Cacao Island
بعد اختفاء مُرشدهم بيكومز، غادر فريق لوفي جزيرة الكاكاو
and is following Pudding's directions to Whole Cake Island
وهو يتبع حاليًّا إرشادات بودينغ إلى جزيرة الكعكة الكاملة
Pirate Emperor, Charlotte Linlin
القراصنة «الإمبراطورة»، شارلوت لينلين
where Emperor Big Mom is.
حيث توجد الإمبراطورة بيغ مام
I'm worried about Pekoms. We gotta look for him!
أنا قلقٌ على بيكومز، علينا أن نبحث عنه
Thank you, but that won't be easy. He's a tough man, so he'll be okay.
ممتنٌ لعرضك لكن سيكون هذا صعبًا
Yeah, but...
...نعم، ولكن
At any rate, we need to get to Whole Cake Island
على أيّة حال، علينا التواري عن أنظار العدوّ
without being seen by the enemy.
حتى نصل إلى جزيرة الكعكة الكاملة
Hey, where are we now?
أين نحن الآن؟
We haven't gone far from Cacao Island yet.
لم نبتعد عن جزيرة الكاكاو كثيرًا
Hey, I see an island!
!أمامنا جزيرة
Yay! What kind of snack will be there?!
مرحى، لا يسعني الانتظار لأرى ما لديهم من حلويات
I can tell from the smell! It must be something sweet!
لا شك من رائحته وحده أنه شيء حلو المذاق
The next one is probably a town made of jam.
التّالية على الأرجح بلدةٌ مَصنوعةٌ من المُربّى
Jam?!
مُربّى؟
But we're not stopping there.
لَن نتوَقّف هناك مع ذلك
Here, look.
هُنا، انظروا
When we spot Jam Island,
عندما نرى جزيرة المُربّى
instead of approaching it, we turn in the direction of the second log pose.
سنلتف باتّجاه البوصلة المسجلة 2 دون أن نقترب منها
But it's sweet! Nami!
لكنّها حُلوَة يا نامي
We're not gonna go there even though it's sweet?!
ألَن نذهب إلى الجزيرة مع أنها حُلوة؟
Let's see...
...لنَر
That way.
من هُناك
Okay!
حسنًا
Luffy, starboard! Turn to three o'clock!
لوفي، إلى المَيمنة باتّجاه الساعة الثالثة
"Sanji" acts as a pun for "three o'clock" That's right! Chopper! Carrot! We're going in the direction of Sanji !
هذا صحيح يا تشوبر وكاروت، سنذهب باتّجاه سانجي
But it's sweet!
لكنّها حُلوَة
We're gonna go pick up Sanji! Hard a-starboard!
سنذهب لأخذ سانجي، إلى أقصى المَيمنة
That's too much!
هذا كثير
You're bad at this, Luffy-san !
أنتَ سيئ في هذا يا لوفي-سان
You too, Brook!
أنتَ أيضًا يا بروك
But it's sweet...!
...لكنّها حُلوَة
By turning toward the next island before getting too close to another one,
ولو التففنا نحو الجزيرة التّالية قبل الاقتراب كثيرًا من الأخرى
we can avoid their surveillance network, she said.
يُمكننا تفادي شبكة مُراقبتهم، كما قالت
Oh, so that's how you read the map.
فهمت، هكذا تُقرأ الخريطة إذًا
Can you do it?
هل يُمكنكَ فعل هذا؟
Count on me.
اعتمدي عليّ
Luffy-san, I'll take it from here.
لوفي-سان، سأستلِم الدفّة الآن
Okay.
حسنًا
Alright, guys, I'll cook something for you!
حسنًا يا رفاق، سأعد لكم بعض الطعام
I gotta cook!
يجب عليّ أن أطهو
Please!
أرجوكِ افعلي
Luffy, wait a second!
انتظر لحظة يا لوفي
What do you want, Nami? I'll cook.
ماذا تُريدين يا نامي؟ سأطهو
No!
كلّا
I'm not gonna mess up this time!
لَن أُفسد الطعام هذه المرّة
I'll do it! Don't you ever set foot in the kitchen again!
أنا من سأطهو، إيّاكَ أن تدخل المَطبخ ثانيةً
I'm not paying you anything!
لَن أدفع لكِ شيئًا
I don't need your money!
لا أحتاج نُقودك
Can I look, Pedro? I wanna help!
دعني أراقب بدلًا عنك يا بيدرو، أريد أن أساعد
Okay.
حسنًا
Let's see...
...لنَر
Hey! The water is grape colored!
انظروا، الماء بلون العِنَب
Grape?
عِنَب؟
There is an island that spills juice around here.
هناك جزيرةٌ تسكب العصير في هذه المنطقة
It's no harm to us.
لَن يُؤذينا هذا
What?! Is that juice?!
ماذا؟ هل ذلك عصير؟
This place is such a paradise!
هذا المكان جنّةٌ بالفِعل
Pedro, how do you know so much about this area?
بيدرو، كيف تعرف الكثير عن هذه المنطقة؟
I've been here once before.
أتيتُ إلى هنا سابقًا
What?
ماذا؟
It's gigantic!
إنّه عملاق
Wow! It's big!
مذهل، إنّه ضخم
It's a giant sea centipede. They reside in this area.
حريش بَحريٍّ عملاق، إنهم يعيشون في هذه المنطقة
No! Giant sea centipede, go away!
كلاّ، الحريش البَحريّ العملاق، ابتعد
We'll be eaten!
سنُؤكَل
Luffy, this is your job!
لوفي، هذه مُهمّتك
All right!
حسنًا
I'll do what little I can too!
سأبذل قدر استطاعتي
Here it comes!
ها هو ذا قادم
Gum-Gum...
غومو غومو نو
Gatling!
غاتلينغ
Meanwhile, on Whole Cake Island...
...خلال ذلك الوَقت، في جزيرة الكعكة الكاملة
Whole Cake Island
جزيرة الكعكة الكاملة
Croquembouche!
!كروكامبوشو
– Mama! Stop! Mama!
ماما، توقفي يا ماما
Mama... Mama, please stop!
ماما... ماما، أرجوكِ توَقّفي
Move!
ابتعدوا
Croquembouche!
كروكامبوشو
Oh, no! It's Mama's illness!
مصيبة، إنّه مَرض ماما
Hurry up-bon ! What does she want this time-soir ?!
أسرِعوا-بون، ماذا تُريد هذه المرّة-سوارو؟
She wants...
...تُريد
croquembouche !
كروكامبوشو
Croquembouche ?!
كروكامبوشو؟
Is that the decorated dessert that is composed of cream puffs piled up?
هل هي الحلوى المُزينة بالكريمة المنفوخة المحشية؟
This will be a challenge.
إعدادُ ذلك سيكون تحدي
Oh! No, wait!
،مهلًا لحظة
I think there is a tourist group of
أظنّ بأنّ هناك مَجموعة سُيّاحٍ
cream puffs staying at a hotel in the city-je-t'aime !
من الكريمة المنفوخة يُقيمون في فُندق العاصمة (فطيرة القشدة)
They already checked out this morning.
رحلوا عنه هذا الصّباح
Should we just make one? What does the chef say?
هل يجب علينا صنعُ واحدة؟ ما هو رأي الطبّاخ؟
I want to make the dough special. Could you get me almonds?
أرغب بجعل العجينة مميزة فأحضر لي اللوز من فضلك
I'll tell the minister of nuts!
سأُخبر وَزير المُكسّرات
Mama is heading toward Sweet City now!
تتّجه ماما نحو مدينة الحلوى الآن
She's coming this way?! This is the capital! Mama's castle is here!
هل هي آتيةٌ إلى هُنا؟ هذه العاصمة، قلعة ماما هُنا
We can't talk her out of it! She's losing her mind from the attack!
لا يجدي الكلام معها نفعًا فقد فقدت صوابها بسبب نوبتها
The death toll is still rising!
عدد القتلى في تزايد
Issue an evacuation order in Sweet City!
اصدروا أمرًا بإخلاء المدينة
Only a croquembouche can stop Mama now!
لن يوقف غضب ماما سوى الكروكامبوشو
This way! Hurry up and evacuate! Hurry up!
من هُنا أسرِعوا وقوموا بالإخلاء، أسرِعوا
Mama, please stop!
ماما، أرجوكِ توقّفي
Mama, let's not do this!
ماما، لا تفعلي هذا
Bring me croquembouche !
أحضروا لي الكروكامبوشو
Mama entered Sweet City! She entered Sweet City!
دخلَت ماما مدينة الحلوى، لَقد دخلَت مدينة الحلوى
Oh, she's finally here...
إنّها هُنا أخيرًا
Mama's ravenous rampage is very troublesome-bon !
نوبات جُوع ماما تتسبّب بالكثير من المتاعب-بون
You don't know when the attack will strike.
نحنُ لا نعلم متى سيضربها الجوع
The destruction continues until she gets a bite of what she craves.
سيستمرّ التّدمير حتّى تأكل ما تشتهيه
It's worse than any kind of disaster.
ما أسوأ الكارثة
Anyway, evacuate all the residents!
على أيّة حال، أخلوا جميع السكّان
Run! Hurry up!
اركضوا أسرِعوا
Big Mom's having a tantrum!
أُصيبَت بيغ مام بنوبة غضب
– Stop! – Not in this city!
توَقّفي- ليس في هذه المدينة-
Mama! Mama! Not in this city!
ماما، ماما لَيس في هذه المدينة
– She'll destroy her own castle! – It's no good. She can't hear us.
ستُدمّر قلعتها- هذا سيّئ، لا يُمكنها أن تسمعنا-
Croquembouche !
كروكامبوشو
This isn't it!
هذا ليس هو
L-Look up!
جـ-جاءت
You losers aren't it either!
وأنتُم كذلك لَستُم هو
It's all wrong!
كلّ شيءٍ خاطئ
Croquembouche !
كروكامبوشو
Thank you!
شُكرًا لك
Oh, it's Minister Moscato!
إنّه موسكاتو-ساما
The 16th son of the Charlotte family and the minister of gelato!
!الابن الـ16 لعائلة شارلوت ووَزير جيلاتو
He's a member of Mama's family! I'm sure he can stop her!
بما أنه فردٌ من عائلة ماما، واثقٌ أنه بإمكانه إيقافها
Charlotte Moscato 16th Son of the Charlotte Family Minister of Gelato
شارلوت موسكاتو، الابن الـ16 لعائلة شارلوت ووَزير جيلاتو
This is Moscato! How's the croquembouche ?!
معكم موسكاتو، ما وَضع الكروكامبوشو؟
I heard it'll take half an hour or so to be ready-bon !
سمعتُ أنّه بحاجةٍ لنِصف ساعةٍ تقريبًا ليُصبح جاهزًا-بون
It'll be too late by then! We can't let her destroy the castle!
سيكون الوَقت تأخّر كثيرًا وَقتها، لا يُمكننا أن نسمح لها بتدمير القلعة
This isn't it!
هذا ليس هو
Mama! Stop it!
توَقفي عن هذا يا ماما
Who is that?!
من ذلك؟
Mama! It's me! Moscato!
هذا أنا موسكاتو يا ماما
Where is my croquembouche ?
أين الكروكامبوشو خاصّتي؟
Croquembouche...
...كروكامبوشو
Croquembouche !
كروكامبوشو
Give us 30 minutes! The chefs are trying to make it as quickly as they can!
اعطِنا 30 دقيقة، الطهاة يُحاولون صُنعه بأقصى سُرعةٍ
No, Big Bro Mos! It's impossible to stop her!
توقف يا موس، من المستحيل إيقافها
I can't let her ruin the capital!
لا يُمكنني السّماح لها بتدمير العاصمة
Move out of my way!
ابتعد عن طريقي
Don't you recognize me, Mama?!
ألم تعرفيني يا ماما؟
Life...
...حياة
or...
...أم
treat!
تحلية...
Life or treat...
...حياة أم تحلية
Lifespan or snack!
إما عمره أو ما يسد جوعها
You gotta be kidding, Mama! He's your own son!
لابدّ من أنكِ تمزحين، إنه ابنكِ يا ماما
Mama, don't do it!
ماما، لا تفعليها
W-We have whipped cream here! No dough yet, but Mama, don't!
لـ- لدينا الكريمة المخفوقة، لكن العجينة لم تُعد بعد، لكن لا تفعليها يا ماما
Th-The treat is not here yet!
ا-الحلوى لَيست هُنا بعد
I'll take the treat.
سآكل الحلوى
Don't get in my way!
لا تقِف في طريقي
Mama!
ماما
Moscato, stay cool!
موسكاتو، ابقَ هادئًا
No! Any sign of fear and your lifespan will be taken away!
إياك-فا، أيّ علامةٍ على الخوف وسيُؤخذ عُمرك-فا
Have mercy, Mama! I won't stop you anymore!
ارحميني يا ماما، لَن أُوقِفكِ بعد الآن
Just please! Don't kill me!
لذا أرجوكِ لا تقتُليني
Give me 40 years.
أربعون عامًا
Big Bro!
أخي الكبير
Minister Moscato!
موسكاتو -ساما
She killed...
...هذا ابنها
her own son!
وقتلته...
Croquembouche !
كروكامبوشو
Run! No one can stop her now!
اهربوا، لا يُمكن لأحدٍ إيقافها الآن
That's terrible.
هذا فظيع
Somebody's coming from the river of juice!
أحدهم قادمٌ من نهر العصير
– That's... – That man is...
...ذلك... ذلك الرجل هو
No doubt!
من دون شكّ
Everyone, move!
فليبتعد الجّميع
Former Warlord Jinbe Captain of the Sun Pirates
جينبي، شيتشيبوكاي سابق وقبطان قراصنة الشّمس
It's Boss Jinbe!
!إنه الزّعيم جينبي
Help!
ساعدونا
We'll be eaten!
سنُؤكل
He has a croquembouche on his side!
يحمل كروكامبوشو إلى جانبه
He caught those tourist cream puffs for us!
لَقد أمسكَ بأولئكَ السيّاح من الكريمة المنفوخة لأجلِنا
They are coated with candy! Did the minister of candy do it?!
تُغلّفهم الحلوى، هل هذا من فِعل وَزير الحلوى؟
Look over here!
من هُنا
Don't get in my way!
لا تعترض طريقي
Catch this!
احشريهم
It's delicious!
إنّه لذيذ
– Yeah! – Mama has cooled down!
نجحَ
This is it!
هذا هو
If it's delicious, that's all that matters...
ما دام الطعم شهي، فهذا ما يهم
Thank you, Boss Jinbe!
شُكرًا لك أيّها الزّعيم جينبي
Let the chefs know! The crisis is over!
ابلغوا الطهاة أن الأزمة انتهت
Summon all the ministers!
استدعوا جميع الوُزراء
Restore the capital as rapidly as possible-bon !
أعيدوا بناء العاصمة بأقصى سرعة-بون
Oh, my loyal Jinbe, Knight of the Sea!
يا فارسي البحري الوفيّ جينبي
Good job bringing me the poneglyph the other day.
أحسنتَ بإحضار البونغليف لي ذلك اليوم
Queen Charlotte Linlin of Totto Land One of the Four Emperors, Big Mom Pirates’ Captain
شارلوت لينلين، إحدى الأباطرة الأربعة ملِكة توتولاند وقُبطانة قراصنة بيغ مام
I can't read it, though.
لا يُمكنني قِراءته مع ذلك
What do you want today? Why are we out here?
ما شأنك اليوم؟ ما جاء بك إلى هنا؟
Oh? The city is looking better than ever.
عجبًا، تبدو المدينة بشكلٍ أفضل من العادة
Did you do this?
هل فعلتَ هذا؟
No, I just arrived, and I have no clue what happened, ma'am.
كلا، وصلت لتوي ولا أملك فكرة عمّا حصل
I'm here...
...أتيت لرؤيتك اليوم
to tell you something important today.
من أجل أن أطلعك على شأنٍ في غاية الأهمية...
You're not gonna leave my crew, are you?
لَن تترُك طاقمي، أليس كذلك؟
A Few Hours Ago...
قبل بضع ساعات
Straw Hat Luffy will change the world someday!
قبعة القش لوفي هو الرجل الذي سيغير العالم يومًا ما
I know he is still young, but I don't think any one of the
أعلم أنه ما يزال يافعًا، لكن لقب ملك البحار
current Four Emperors will become the king of the sea!
لن يحمله أيٍّ من الأباطرة الأربعة الحاليين
I think Straw Hat Luffy will be the one!
أظن أن قُبّعة القشّ لوفي سيكون حامله
I...
...أنا
want to be of help to him!
أريد أن أعاون ذلك الرجل
I'm too...
أنا... ضعيف
I... I want to get on board his ship
أنا... أُريد أن أكون على متن سفينة طاقم قبعة القش
and dedicate my life to him!
وأن أُكرّس حياتي لـ لوفي
I believe that journey will bring true freedom to the fishmen in the end!
أُؤمن بأنّ تلك الرحلة ستجلِب الحريّة الحقيقيّة للبرمائيين في نهايتها
Aladine (A Brotula Merman) First Mate of the Sun Pirates
(علاء الدين (حُوريّ بروتولا نائب قبطان قراصنة الشّمس
For the last two years,
خلال العامين المنصرمين، أخبرتَنا بالكثير عن لوفي-كن
I've been thinking you should go join him if you like him so much.
كنتُ أُفكّر بأنّه يجب عليكَ الذّهاب للانضمام إليه إن كنتَ تُحبّه كثيرًا
D-Did I really?!
هـ-هل أنت جاد؟
Did I talk about him so much?!
هل تحدّثتُ عنه كثيرًا؟
Go, Jinbe!
اذهب يا جينبي
Are you sure?
هل أنتَ وَاثق؟
No one here has the right to object, Captain!
لا أحد هُنا يملك الحقّ للاعتراض أيها القُبطان
Yeah! You were a soldier of the Neptune Army, but you became a pirate
نعم، كنتَ جُنديًّا في جيش نبتون لكنّكَ أصبحتَ قُرصانًا
to fight with us, the former slaves who fled from Mary Geoise!
لتنضم للعبيد الهاربين من الماريجوا وتقاتل معنا
You became a warlord to help advance the social status of us fishmen!
أصبحتَ شيتشيبوكاي لتساعد في تعزيز وَضعنا الاجتماعيّ، نحن البرمائيين
And you allied with the Big Mom Pirates
وتحالفتَ مع قراصنة بيغ مام
to protect us and our home, the Ryugu Kingdom, under Big Mom's name.
لحمايتنا نحن ووَطننا مملكة ريوغو تحت اسم بيغ مام
You've always made choices for the sake of others!
اتّخذتَ القرارات دائمًا لأجل مصلحة الآخرين
You've done enough, Jinbe.
لقد فعلتَ ما يكفي يا جينبي
Yeah! Be free, Jinbe-san !
هذا صحيح، عش حرًّا لنفسك يا جينبي-سان
– Go, Jinbe! – Yeah, Captain Jinbe!
صحبتك السلامة يا جينبي
We'll be fine without you. Don't underestimate us!
سنكون بخير من دونك، لا تستخفّ بنا
Live for yourself from now on!
عِش لأجل نفسكَ من الآن فصاعدًا
You guys... Thank you!
أيها الرفاق... شكرًا لكم
Having said that... I don't think Big Mom will let the captain go so easily.
بقول هذا، لا أظنّ بأن بيغ مام ...ستُفلت قبطاننا بهذه السهولة
If she gets mad at us too, all we can do is run!
إن غضبَت منا أيضًا، كلّ ما سنتمكّن من فعله هو الهرب
But what about Aladine-san ?
لكن ماذا عن علاء الدين-سان؟
He got married to Madam Praline and became a member of Big Mom's family.
تزوج من السيدة برالين وأصبح فردًا من عائلة البيغ مام
Oh?
عجبي، عجبي
Are you guys worried about me?
هل أنتم قلِقون بشأني؟
Oh, Madam!
بئسًا، ني-سان
Charlotte Praline (Half-Human, Half-Hammerhead Shark Mermaid) 21st Daughter of the Charlotte Family
الابنة الـ 29 لعائلة شارلوت، شارلوت برالين (نصف بشر ونصف سمك قرش المطرقة)
Are you talking behind my back?
هل تتحدثون عني بالخِفية؟
Did you hear what we said?!
هل سمعت ما قلناه؟
Hey, are you trying to hide something from me?!
هل تحاول إخفاء شيء عني؟
Aladine! Don't tell me you were gonna leave me behind if Mama gets angry!
علاء الدين، تُرى هل كنت ستتركني خلفك إن غضبَت ماما؟
No, of course, I'd ask you...
...كلّا، بالتّأكيد سأطلُب منكِ
You don't need to ask!
لا حاجة لأن تطلُب
I'll definitely choose you over Mama! If anything happens, take me with you!
سأختارك على ماما بالتأكيد إن حصل أيّ شيء، خُذني معك
Oh, so passionate!
شغفها حبها
Sorry, Wadatsumi.
أعتذر يا واداتسومي
I just brought you here, but as you heard, I've got to go.
لقد أحضرتكَ إلى هنا للتو، ولكن كما سمعت، عليّ أن أذهب
That's okay! I'm so happy to be with these guys.
لا بأس، أنا سعيد بكوني مع الرفاق
Now, Praline, don't you think Mama will forgive me... I mean, us?
والآن يا برالين، هل تظنين بأن ماما لن تسامحني... أعني نحن؟
Well, there were precedents, but those who wished to leave her crew...
...حصلَت سوابق، لكن من رغبوا بترك طاقمها
are all dead.
قد ماتوا جميعًا
The Present: Whole Cake Island
الحاضر في جزيرة الكعكة الكاملة
Sweet City Capital of Whole Cake Island
مدينة الحلوى عاصمة جزيرة الكعكة الكاملة
Minister Moscato!
موسكاتو-ساما
Minister Moscato is dead!
لقد مات موسكاتو-ساما
Don't die, Minister Moscato!
لا تمُت يا موسكاتو-ساما
Minister Moscato!
موسكاتو-ساما
They're finally here.
وصلوا أخيرًا
Hurry up and take him away.
أسرعوا وخُذوه بعيدًا
Yes, ma'am.
حاضر
Step back.
تراجع
Listen, guys.
اسمعوا يا رفاق
Every last second. Okay?
حتّى آخر ثانية، أفهمتم؟
Minister Moscato...
...موسكاتو-ساما
Say, do you think Boss Jinbe will be killed too, Minister Mont d'Or?!
أخبرني، هل تظنّ بأنّ الزّعيم جينبي سيُقتَل أيضًا يا مونت دور-ساما؟
How should I know?!
كيف لي أن أعلم؟
When someone makes Mama angry, this is surely what happens,
عندما يُغضِب أحدهم ماما، هذا ما سيحصل بالتأكيد
even if it's her own son!
حتى لو كان ابنها
Sweet City Whole Cake Chateau
قصر الكعكة الكاملة في مدينة الحلوى
I guess you're leaving, Jinbe.
أظنك ستغادر، صحيح؟
– Why, Boss?! – Don't leave, Boss! Why do you have to leave?!
لماذا أيها الزعيم؟
Shut up!
اخرسوا
Don't ask someone why they're leaving! That's pathetic!
لا تسألوا أحدًا عن سبب مغادرته، هذا مثير للشفقة
Who cares?!
من يهتمّ لهذا؟
If you're a pirate, of course you want to live as you like.
إن كنت قرصانًا، بالتأكيد سترغب بالعيش كما تشاء
Am I delicious? Tell me, am I...?!
...هل أنا لَذيذ؟ أخبريني ، هل أنا
Having said that,
بقول هذا
having a pledge of loyalty reneged brings shame to a lord.
تعهد الولاء الذي يُنكَث يجلِب العار على السيد
Jinbe, you know this means I'm going to lose a powerful asset: you.
جينبي، تعلم أنّ مغادرتك تعني بأنّني سأخسر أحد أصولي القويّة
Yes, but...
...نعم، لكن
No "but"! You should lose something too!
دون «لكن»! عليك خسارة شيءٍ أيضًا
You have to pay a price!
يجب أن تدفع الثمن
Bring me the roulette!
أحضروا لي الروليت
What?
ماذا؟
Now, spin it.
الآن، لُفّها
I can't wait to see what you're gonna lose!
والآن، ما الذي ستخسره يا ترى؟
Meanwhile, Luffy and the others are sailing through Big Mom's territory.
خلال ذلك الوقت، كان لوفي والآخرون داخل مياه إقليم بيغ مام
So sweet!
حُلوٌ جدًّا
Anyway, it's not moving a bit.
يا للعجب، إنّها لا تتحرّك على الإطلاق
No...
...حقًا
Well, let's just stay here and sleep!
لا تبالِ، لنبقَ هنا وننام
No! What if those ants attack us again?!
كلّا، ماذا لو هاجمتنا تلك الحشرات ثانيةً؟
When the sun rises, it'll begin to flow again.
عندما تشرق الشمس، ستعود للجريان ثانيةً
But during the night, it gets cold and solidifies.
لكن خِلال فترة المَساء، تبرد وتتجمّد
Share those things beforehand!
يا ليتك شاركتنا هذه المعلومات مُسبقًا
We've gotta melt it and get out of this area of starch syrup!
يجب أن نُذيبها ونخرج من منطقة شراب النشا هذه
Yeah!
نعم
We just put the army of ants to sleep!
لَقد أنمنا للتّوّ جيشًا من النّمل
It's gonna be trouble when they wake up.
ستكون مشكلةً عندما يستيقظون
That's right.
هذا صحيح
Those sea ants once ate my ship.
نمل البحر هذا الْتهمَ سفينتي في الماضي
Oh, my!
مخيف
Once? What did you come here for?
في الماضي؟ لماذا أتيت إلى هنا؟
Pedro used to be a pirate along with Pekoms.
كان بيدرو قرصانًا مع بيكومز
What?! Really?!
ماذا؟ حقًّا؟
I was so naive.
كنتُ ساذجًا جدًّا
I thought of myself as an explorer, but I became a wanted person.
خرجتُ مستكشفًا وغدوت شخصًا مَطلوبًا
I only accompanied Pekoms halfway.
رافقتُ بيكومز لمُنتصف الطريق فقط
I trust you people, so I can tell you.
أثق بكم فسأخبركم
I was looking for poneglyphs because I wanted to help Master Nekomamushi.
كنتُ أبحث عن البونغليف لأنّني أردتّ مُساعدة السيّد نيكوماموشي
But when I trespassed in Big Mom's territory, it became my last voyage.
لكن عندما دخلتُ منطقة بيغ مام، أصبحَت هذه رحلتي الأخيرة
I...
...أنا
was defeated here once.
هُزِمتُ هنا في الماضي
I've seldom told anyone about this.
لَم أخبر أحدًا عن هذا
I didn't know that.
لم أعلم بهذا
You have bad memories, yet you came back?
أتيت إلى هنا رغم ذكرياتك السيئة؟
If my experience helps you even a little bit to take back Sanji, I'll be happy.
إن كانت خبرتي ستساعدكم ولَو قليلًا حتّى على استعادة سانجي، سأكون سعيدًا
On top of that,
علاوةً على ذلك
maybe it wasn't so bad that I came along.
ربما لم يكن من السيئ قدومي معكم
I heard our kings showed you people the lode poneglyph at the Whale Tree.
سمعت بأن ملِكينا قد أرياكم بونغليف الطريق داخل شجرة الحوت
I was surprised.
أصابتني الدهشة
Even though you may have saved us,
رغم أنكم أنقذتمونا
they haven't shown it to anybody other than the Kozuki clan...
لم يرياه لأحد عدا عشيرة الكوزكي
for 26 years...
لـ26 عامًا
since they showed it to Gol D. Roger's pirate group.
منذ أن أرياه لقراصنة غول دي روجر
The pirate king?!
ملك القراصنة؟
Later, Roger reached Laugh Tale and was called the pirate king.
وصل روجر بعدها إلى لافتيل ودُعيَ بملك القراصنة
You people remind Duke Inuarashi and Master Nekomamushi of them.
أنتم تذكّرون الدوق إينواراشي والسيد نيكوماموشي بهم
They're expecting you to become somebody who'll need the lode poneglyphs.
ارتئيا أنكم بحاجة لبونغليف طريق
What are you gonna do after you defeat Kaido?
ماذا ستفعلون بعد أن تهزموا كايدو؟
That's too far ahead! I haven't thought about it...
أنا لا أفكر في الخطوة التالية من الآن
Next, you'll need the lode poneglyph that Big Mom has!
لاحقًا، ستحتاجون إلى بونغليف الطريق التي تملكها بيغ مام
If so, this would be our biggest chance!
إذًا، هذه ستكون أفضل فرصة لنا
Since we came this deep into her territory,
بما أننا تعمقنا لهذا المدى في منطقتها
we'd better steal Big Mom's lode poneglyph in addition to taking back Sanji!
من الأفضل أن نسرق بونغيليف الطريق التي تخصّ بيغ مام إضافةً إلى استعادة سانجي
What? But that's...
...ماذا؟ لكن هذا
Not just Sanji, but also a lode poneglyph?
ليس سانجي فقط ولكن أيضًا بونغليف الطريق؟
Well, Robin asked me to get it too, but I wanna rescue Sanji first...
حسنًا، طلبت مني روبين إحضاره أيضًا، لكنني أريد إنقاذ سانجي أولًا
I know.
أعلم
I'll get the lode poneglyph. You guys go for Sanji.
سأحصل على بونغليف الطريق، فأنقذوا أنتم سانجي
When we reach the island, could I have a little time?
!عندما نصل إلى الجزيرة، هلا تمهلونني بعض الوقت
This time, I'll get it!
هذه المرة، سأحصل عليه
No, but if you're doing it for us, we'll come with you!
لكن إن كنت تفعل هذا لأجلنا فسنرافقك
No, you make sure to protect Sanji.
كلا، تأكدوا من أن تحموا سانجي
Even after you get him back, things will be tough.
سيظلّ الوضع عصيبًا حتى بعد استعادته
Okay. Then I'll leave it to you!
فهمت، سأدع الأمر إليك إذًا
Great!
تقرر الأمر
Don't decide so easily!
لا تُقرر بهذه البساطة
I wonder if Luffy-san was born to be lucky...
وكأن لوفي-سان وُلد محظوظًا
What is it, Brook?
ما الأمر يا بروك؟
Nothing. I'm also lucky.
لا شيء، أنا محظوظ أيضًا
What are you talking about? You're weird.
ما الذي تتحدث عنه؟ أنت غريب الأطوار
Oh, the ants are awake!
!استيقظ النمل
Here they come!
ها هم قادمون
Save the Sunny !
!احموا الساني
The Next Day...
اليوم التالي
Hey, guys!
!يا رفاق
Wake up!
استيقظوا
Huh? What is it?
ما الأمر؟
Look! Look!
انظروا، انظروا
We're here finally!
وصلنا أخيرًا
Wow, it's gigantic!
مذهل، إنها ضخمة
So this is where an emperor lives!
هذه الجزيرة التي تقطن فيها الإمبراطورة
There's a cake!
إنها كعكة
That tallest whole cake is a castle where Big Mom lives.
الكعكة الكاملة هي القلعة التي تسكنها بيغ مام
A castle?!
قلعة؟
Nami-san, we'll continue on straight like this?
نامي-سان، هل سنستمر بطريق مباشر هكذا؟
Yes, that cape is the only place without security.
نعم، ذلك الخليج هو الوحيد بلا حراسة
I see.
فهمت
That's the place Pudding-san mentioned.
ذلك هو المكان الذي ذكرته بودينغ-سان
Yeah, we have to really thank her.
نعم، يجب أن نشكرها حقًّا
If it weren't for her, I don't know if we could've made it this far.
لولاها ما كنا لنتمكن من الوصول إلى هذا المدى
You're right.
أنت محقة
Hey, somebody's there!
أحدهم هناك
Sanji?
سانجي؟
Is that Sanji?! Hey!
هل ذاك سانجي؟
Sanji!
!سانجي